hey everyone welcome to another
interesting Tosca lesson in this session
I am going to talk about how you can
compare two PDF files using a t-box
module
so you don't need to write any
particular test cases or you don't need
to create any modules a module is
already provided in the standard subset
which can be used to compare to PDF
files okay so I've created uh already a
test case folder called PDF comparison
for this comparison I'm going to use two
PDF files these are not exactly same
there is some difference in both the
files right so if you are going to
compare these two files uh you will see
that uh the test case will fail if you
have provided a hundred percent accuracy
now we'll talk about that uh when we
open the module but just looking at the
PDF file so it's a PDF file which is
generated in one of the sample
applications which is the vehicle
insurance application so it looks like
that
so it looks like this it has just got
one page okay
but you can also compare multiple uh
Pages uh in your PDFs okay
okay
um so let's go ahead and add our module
now okay so let me add this case here
and I'm going to call it compare PDF
and then let's search for this compare
PDF so when you type compare the first
option is one is to one compare now we
have already seen some of the other
t-box modules like file compare you can
also compare images right and also a
Excel file
so when you use this one to one compare
okay we need to provide the reference
and the target PDF so reference PDF is
the PDF which will act as a reference
for the comparison and the target would
be uh the PDF which you want to compare
this reference PDF with okay
we can also if
if your PDF is password protected you
can also specify the password here and
Tosca will automatically enter that
password while comparing the PDF okay
same for Target PDF
now I was talking about uh the accuracy
which is in percentage okay so we can
Define our own accuracy so it's
basically the percentage of uh accuracy
which you want for your comparison okay
uh you can specify 100 accuracy which
means both the PDF should be exactly
same you can also decrease the accuracy
if you are not worried about uh so much
about uh some of the things in the PDF
which may not be same
so it depends on uh what kind of
accuracy you require for this comparison
okay and then excluded pages so here you
can specify which Pages you want to
exclude uh from the comparison so if you
have got multiple pages in your PDF
files you can exclude some of the pages
from the comparison okay
so uh we have to provide a reference PDF
as I said okay so this is the path of
the file which you want to compare
so let's provide that
okay and don't forget to also provide
the extension which is dot PDF uh we
don't require a password for this and
let's copy this for the reference and
we'll just change the name here
to code two okay
I will just correct the name here to
quote underscore 2. and then uh you need
to specify our accuracy so first of all
I'll provide a 80 accuracy okay
and excluded Pages although I don't have
multiple pages in my PDF but if you have
then you can provide
some values like this okay
so what this will do is uh you can
provide multiple uh page Pages which you
want to exclude so in this case it will
exclude the first page the three to four
page and the five page okay so which has
to be separated by semicolon uh you can
also
combine your pages like a range like
this page to this page you want to
exclude okay or individual Pages depends
on you
so this is how you can exclude your PDF
pages from comparison and these are the
module attributes which you need to pass
okay
now if I go ahead and compare or run
this particular test case
you will see that uh this test case will
pass even though the PDF files are
different okay
uh the reason being uh the accuracy
percentage okay since the accuracy
percentage is 80 percent okay so in the
results you can see uh in log info that
it will say that the success condition
was met and that is why this test case
passed so each page of the Target and
the Baseline document
is at least a 80 percent match okay and
we have not uh we have no Pages excluded
from the comparison
okay now uh to just to change it if I
provide a hundred percent accuracy okay
you want your comparison to be 100
accurate for both the PDFs and that's a
fair uh Fair way of doing it right so
just run
and this time it should fail okay
because both the PDFs are not 100 same
okay and uh in the compare results in
log info
you will see that it will show you the
differences okay so at least one
difference was detected
and in the top left area top right mid
left mid right and bottom right area
okay
obviously it will not uh exactly tell
you what is different in this particular
pages but it's basically uh used for
quick comparison of two PDF documents if
you want to verify uh certain elements
on the PDF then you need to use our you
need to create your own test case and
then you need to use the PDF scan okay
we will see that in some of the coming
up session but using the PDF scan then
you can scan particular elements and you
can verify whether they are same on the
PDF or not
but this module is meant for a quick
comparison uh with a certain accuracy
and you can also exclude pages so quite
a useful module if you just want to
compare to PDFs okay
so that's that's all about uh how you
can compare to PDF files using this one
is to one compare the Box module in the
next session uh we'll talk about the PDF
scan how you can scan different elements
in the PDF
and how you can verify the values